Finding aid for the Xavier University Faculty Handbook collection
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Faculty Handbook collection
1956-2010
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Faculty Handbook Committee
1 linear feet (2 boxes)
This is a collection of Xavier University Faculty handbooks with meeting minutes of two committees charged with forming editions of the faculty handbook.
XUA- 28
History of Xavier University Faculty Handbook Committee
On at least two occasions an ad hoc committee of faculty members and administrators was established to revise the Xavier faculty handbook. The first Faculty Handbook Committee met during the academic year 1966-67, resulting in the handbook that appeared in 1967. The second Faculty Handbook Committee for which we have records met from April 11, 1995 to April 8, 1998. Its work resulted in the 2000 handbook.
Scope and Content
This collection comprises editions of the Xavier University Faculty Handbook. Also included are the meeting minutes for two of the ad hoc committees formed to revise the handbook. Two publications used by one of the committees is also included.
Statement of Arrangement
The bulk of the collection is arranged into faculty handbooks arranged chronologically and then by committee meeting minutes arranged chronologically.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Faculty--Handbooks, manuals, etc.
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Faculty Handbook Committee
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Faculty Handbook First Edition, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Faculty Handbook 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Faculty Handbook 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Faculty Handbook Circa 1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Faculty Handbook College of Continuing Education,Summer Sessions, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Faculty Handbook 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Faculty Handbook 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Faculty Handbook 1990, Second Copy (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Faculty Handbook 2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Faculty Handbook 2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Faculty Handbook 2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Adjunct (Part Time) Faculty Manual Two Versions, approximately 1998-2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Faculty Handbook Committee Meeting Minutes, 1966,1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- AAUP Policy Documents and Reports, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Beckham Faculty/Staff Non-renewal and Dismissal for Cause..., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)